<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<models>
<journal author="Stanley Hayami">
    <entry page="Recto 10">
        <p1><month>Dec</month>. <day>7</day>, <year>1942</year></p1>
        <p2>Today was the day last year in which this whole mess started. 
            Last year it was Sunday.</p2>
        <p3>I was busy outside that morning so I didn't hear about it when it happened. 
            However in the afternoon business slowed down to a stand still. 
            Not a customer came for about an hour so I went back to the house 
            and turned on the radio. The announcer kept butting in 
            "Attention to all men in service, Report at once to your 
            station, all leave canceled." Then tuning in on a news broadcast 
            I heard the stunning news. “<place>Pearl Harbor</place> bombed!! 
            About fifty planes came over the harbor at etc.” 
            I turned off the radio and rushed out front and told
            <person>pa</person> and <person>ma</person>.</p3>
        <p4>That night we all felt as if we were in still having a nightmare. 
            <person>Obasan</person> called and told about what was happening in <place>LA</place>. 
            That night we all went to sleep wondering what was going to happen to us. 
            Little did I know then that one year from then I 
            would be in <place>Heart Mt Wyo.</place> in a evacuation camp.</p4>
</entry>
    <entry page="Verso 10">
        <p1><month>Dec</month>. <day>8</day>, <year>1942</year></p1>
        <p2>Today, last year I went to school excited, scared 
        (tho I had no reason to be) and sort of embarrassed. 
        When I went to class everyone was talking about it and 
        I felt a little conspicuous as if everyone was looking at me. 
        The rest of the kids said hello to me as usual and all tried 
        to keep off the topic of war. However I didn't feel much like 
        talking about anything that day. All during English class my 
        English teacher had the news broadcast on. One report was coming 
        from <place>Manila</place> and was cut short as Jap. planes 
        began flying over. After I got home I did little else except 
        listening to news reports.</p2>
        <p3>Today I took my physical exam.</p3>
        <p4><image type="cartoon"></image></p4>
        <p5>Hmm Maybe You're Dead.</p5>
    </entry>
</journal>
<journal author="Margaretta Hirsch Doyle " year="1944">
    <entry>
        <p1>Wea. <month>May</month> <day>1</day> Ther.</p1>
        <p2>A typical Monday, with song, practice, and 
            sorority meeting - nothing terribly interesting.</p2>
        <p3> I did more work on the marketing survey, 
            and sunbathed awhile this afternoon.</p3>
        <p4><person>Bill Brennan</person> sent me a card. He 
            expects a furlough this month - not while I’m home 
            though. All chances for a commission are out for him.</p4>
        <p5>I got a nice letter from <person>Bill Hughes</person>. 
            He is in Scotland - just been made a Chief Party Officer.</p5>
    </entry>
</journal>
<journal author="Emma Wormwood" year="1895-1896">
    <entry page="10"> 
        <p1><person>Orah</person> and <person>Stella</person> called.</p1>
    </entry>
    <entry page="10">
        <p1><month>September</month> <date>10</date>th. <dow>Tuesday.</dow></p1>
        <p2> Very warm. Nineteen pupils at school. 
            -Sang, "Learn a Little Every Day" Came home early. 
            Drank some new cider. At supper, laughed about 
            "The old Hen" and "Watermelons."</p2>
    </entry>
    <entry page="10">
        <p1><month>September</month> <day>11</day>th <dow>Wednesday</dow>.</p1>
        <p2> Hazy looking but warm. Must go to school early and sweep.
            Too hot to study. Two new pupils. Came home early
            - Threshers were waiting for the machine.
            (The man who keeps the Restaurant sits up 
            "like a toad before a thunder-shower".</p2>
    </entry>
    <entry page="10">
        <p1><month>September</month> <day>12</day>th <dow>Thursday</dow>.</p1>
        <p2>Hot as ever. Came home and went to the orchard 
            - tasted winter apples. Went to party at 
            <person>Miss Myrtie King</person>'s. About 65 or 70 guests 
            present. Played floor games. All seemed to enjoy themselves.
            Met quite a number of</p2>
    </entry>
</journal>
</models>